and feel feel free to interrupt me if
you have anything unclear or you have
any
questions
um so the content of starting from today
and the following classes will be
arranged as follows so we are going to
firstly talk about different techniques
that are commonly used nowadays for
robot learning such as reinforcement
learning Behavior Colonial visual
imitations
and by the end of the uh the semester we
also study uh we'll present case studies
or research projects that use these
techniques so the purpose of this
lecture is to introduce you some basic
and useful knowledges and to help you
understand where you where you where you
are presented um of the case studies on
Locomotion navigation so dexus
manipulation and reinforcement learning
and simil are kind of very commonly used
in local motion and manipulation so the
topic today will be closely related to
that
part and in today's lecture specifically
we are going to firstly review some
basic reinforcement learning or RL
Basics so RL is a prerequisite for this
class so hopefully you already know most
of the concept and then we will also
talk about uh some of the attempts to
apply applying RL to Robotics and their
limitations their challenges and why
they do not immediately work and after
that we also take uh a small detour to
talk about one important de line of
development which is the
simulators and
which uh simulate we talk about
simulators and also together some
algorithmic improvements and also
engineering effort that finally makes RL
for robotics Works
nowadays and finally we will also
present a small case studies on openi De
first hand together with highspeed drone
racing to talk about how we apply this
concept on real world
Robotics and let's start from the
firstly reinforcement learning
review um our Target is to have a robot
or an agent to interact with the word
and by receiving feedbacks from the
environments so from the environment
feedback it the agent can adjust Its
Behavior accordingly so this assumption
or a simple and reasonable mathematical
model we can have is something we called
Mark of decision
process and in this in this formulation
the environment will provide the agent
some a collection of states that defines
the environment and the agent will
according to this state perform some
kind of actions and send this action to
the
environment and the environment given
the current state as T and also receive
some agents output the state will change
and how it change is defined by this
transition Dynamics given St and at it
outputs some SD plus one and meanwhile
it also produce a reward function which
tells the agent if if the action is good
or not depending on the task uh so for
different task you have different reward
functions that will guide the agents
Behavior so the reinforcement learning
the target of reinforcement learning is
to find some policy or controller Pi
star that
maximize a a trajectory of reverse so in
this case you have a expectation over
different uh policy action distributions
and then you are trying to maximize
summation from tal to Z to capital T and
you sum over all the rewards uh and
you're trying to maximize this
term and there are just too many new uh
algorithms to optimize this objective
depending on from which angle you are
viewing these algorithms it can be
roughly divided by also can be divided
by different ways so depending on if
you're going to care about the trans
learning the transition Dynamics it can
be categorized by modelbased RL or model
free RL the model here is the like the
transition Dynamics models and depending
on if you uh want to learn only consider
learning the policies or you also want
to learning only the value functions it
can also be categorized into policy
based or value based or somehow Al some
Middle Ground of these two method which
is actor critic line of work and
depending on what type of data you are
going to use is that so the data you use
to optimize your policy is that
necessarily come from your polic your
policy itself or come from other data
source uh it can also be divided to
other on policy algorithms or off policy
algorithms and in this lecture um
depending on the relationship to the
robotics content also depending on the
time we only to talk about one class of
that which is model free actor critique
and on policy
algorithms um the development of that
comes from a very straightforward me
meod algori or algorithms called
reinforce so uh this is this is just one
example is the game of Pawn so it's a
Atari game that there are two players
each of them controlling the the board
to move up and down and the goal is
always to make the ball pass the the uh
pass the other players board and then
going to the edge of the other
boundaries
and you will Reserve negative reward or
positive reward depending on why if you
are successfully doing so so imagine you
have some agent and usually what we
nowadays do is having a neuron Network
that directly takes the image input and
output some actions and these actions
can simply be if it's zero it moves
downward if it's one it moves upward so
the one difference between RL and
uh supervised learning is you do not
have a very concrete definition of what
is the label is so of course so there
are also uh in the next lecture we might
talk about Behavior cloning which you
have human labels that but in more in in
a more General formulation of
reinforcement learning we want to
learning from the reward provided by the
environment to guide this policy Network
to uh win the game so um the way we can
do that is instead of relying on the
labels we can sample a lot of different
trajectories by the policy so imagine
you have some policy that randomly
initialized at the beginning and you
collect a different trajectories in the
environment so sometimes uh it get a
sequence of up down up up down down down
and it leads to win and there are also
other cases lead to lose and there are
some relative difference between the re
reward which tells you which kind of
decision is good and which is not which
is not good so this kind of learning
signal we can use that to guide the
policy learning and
uh get the policy learning and becomes I
can perform the task better and better
and more mathematical formulation so
this is directly taken from the
reinforcement learning class in Berkeley
so we are going to the first uh the
first equation is essentially the
objective of reinforcement learning we
want to Maxim we want to find a policy
Theta uh which is the neuron Network
weight that can maximize the expected
return and this is when you actually do
not have the expectation but you only
have a set of maybe thousands hundreds
of trajectories and how you're going to
evaluate that is to sum is average over
all these kind of trajectories
and
um after some very interesting and
clever like mathematical derivations and
this turns out you can it's relatively
easy to take a gradient of that
objective and you can get the gradient
of the objective is some term very
similar to supervised learning term and
it's and as a result it's also very easy
to Implement in mod py
libraries and uh so the formulation what
make what makes the formulation
interesting is that it's a weighted
average of this part so which is very
similar to if you have your supervised
learning algorithm and there is not the
not the pi Theta but the neuron Network
predictions and it's weighted average by
the reward functions so what it says is
actually if you are reward if for uh for
the trajectory you are collecting if the
reward of a certain trajectory is higher
it will make the policy have a gradient
towards that trajectories so after you
have iterations over this uh formulation
again and again the trajectories like
the policy distributions of all possible
trajectories generated by the P policy
we soon convert this to somewhere that
can result into a high reward term
and
um more concretely if you write the re
reinforced algorithms it just simply
involves you sample a lot of
trajectories according to your network
and then you according to these
formulations take gradient of uh take
gradient and then doing SGD step uh
using some popular uh optimizers
so reinforce is a very straightforward
to implement and the basic policy
gradient
algorithms however it also has a lot of
problems and one of the major problems
comes from the idea of uh evaluating
performance of different trajectories
so in this uh in this step if we want to
have a very stable gradient that is
helpful for policy learning we kind of
want to the evaluation to be smooth and
low wance which means that if in a
current state if in the same state we
are going to take two similar actions we
want the like the sum of the rewards to
be similar but uh but the difference in
reinforcement learning is that you are
taking a long trajectory of different
state and actions and your policy is
stochastic instead of deterministic so
even though you have the smooth
transitions at the current step and
after you take 100 other steps the
reward might be very
different so and so this is one of the
motivations the other motivations is
actually we don't care about the
absolute values of your trajectory word
reward because it's very hard to compare
what is the reward mean by saying reward
is 100 versus
1,000 so what we care about is the
relative improvements on a on a state uh
between two
actions and there are also some other
rich literatures on these Q functions
value functions action functions but
essentially we are going to Define some
kind of fancy terms which so firstly is
the Q function which tells you from the
current state St if you're going to take
action a so what is the goodness of the
action at and measured by what is the
expectation over different reward after
you take the action
at and value function is um built value
function is defined on top of Q
functions which measures the goodness of
the state instead of the actions so the
way it calculate is that you consider
all possible actions generated by your
policy and evaluate a vated summation of
all of
them and after we have these two
quantities we can Define some Advantage
functions and which is at a current St
if you are going to take action what is
the difference between you take it
action and you stay as the mean uh at
this state you take the mean actions at
this state so that's called the
advantage because it's the advantage of
the action compared to uh like average
actions you can take in this state in
the current
state and compare an actor critic is
really simply just replace the is you
summation over the reverse functions
over all the trajectories and you change
that term to be Advantage functions so
there are a lot
um yes so there are a lot of also there
are a lot of explanations of from
different aspects on why are you doing
this but I think from my perspective
you're going to learning a neural
network that's trying to feed this uh
trying to get this action function by
fitting this value functions and the
advantage is so firstly after so you can
see a lot of different datas across this
episode so instead of just so the value
is not only estimate from the current
batch of data you also get a lot of you
also get from the training from the
beginning of the training to the end of
training you're continuously fitting
this value functions by using all the
datas you have um so this is one thing
you can so the the uh so the value
function by seeing a lot of different
datas it can get better estimates on the
current state and also because in this
case you always get you always get a
limited number of trajectories so
sometimes if the trajectory is too small
this estimate maybe a very high variance
but if you have a value function um it
consider like for the same reason you
see all of kind of data so you kind of
can get a smooth behaviors just
naturally provided by the neuron
Network
um so that's the actor critic uh where
one missing part is I forgot to mention
the the neuron Network learns is the VT
here and the at the advantage function
can be derived from the current the
reward fun reward defined the current
step and plus the value function at the
next St step and minus the value
function at the current St
step and actor critic solves a lot of
problems of vanilla reinforce but there
are like it increase the training
stabilities it also increase performance
but the problem is um in the development
of AR algorithms people realize policy
is very easy to collapse so collapse
means you have very keep having very
high reward and that s uh and suddenly
after you take one extra gradient steps
the performance just drops dramatic dram
drastically and there is a lot of
research on this by constraining maybe
saying the policy step cannot be too
large by maybe clipping the gradient or
clipping the parameters uh in the
parameter space but uh they do not work
quite well and finally and I think
empirically a best working case is the
proximal policy optimization method
which is also surprisingly simple so uh
consider this this rather complex uh
Expressions so if you if you're focusing
on the advantage functions so this is
what we maximize in the previous actor
actor critics we want to maximize the
advantage function along these policy
generated
trajectories and it takes a minimum
between these terms and these terms and
these terms is defined by the clipping
function depending on if your advantage
function is positive or negative and I'm
going to uh so this is of course the
credit come comes to from this openi
block but it's also very helpful to
understand that so imagine you have a
Advantage function that is positive
which means at the current state you
take this action is good so because this
by definition of the advantage function
is the goodness of this action at this
current state so what we have is firstly
we have this Advantage function and then
also we have this one so Pi Theta K is
the current probability of producing the
desired action uh for the current policy
parameter Theta K and this Pi Theta is
something we are going to optimize in
the next time steps and in this case
what we want is the pi Theta is is what
we want is to produce a higher
probability for Action a because the
advantage function is positive but
meanwhile we also do not want to do not
want the PO the optimization takes step
farther away compared to the current
policy because of the policy collapse
problem so what we do is that is we
consider this ratios we want this ratios
to be greater than one but we do not
want it to be too uh too large so we
will have a clipping term which is one
plus epso this abso is a hyper
parameters typically set to0
one2 and then by clipping this to one
plus Epson uh we usually guaranteeing
that
this so the difference between two
policies is not too large so you are not
taking a very large gradient step that
destroy all of your previous policy
training and similarly is the uh uh when
the advantage is NE
which means the action here is not so
good and we want the probability of
producing these actions to be smaller
than uh compared to in the previous time
step and by the same logic we want this
one to be smaller than one but also not
so small and in this case uh we have we
are going to have another cing terms uh
which which get the policy uh which
guides the policy to be staying close to
the original policy
okay uh so that's the first part any
questions so you're are changing K
during your training for example after
you uh train for 10 steps then you also
update K by
like uh so this so the seta I mean the k
is maybe not very meaningful here so
it's just the saying this is after seta
K you're going to 2 plus produce Theta
k+ one which is this
Theta oh I so the case precisely the
policy from the P
yeah okay and next we are going to talk
about uh attempts to applying RL to
Robotics and if you think about maybe
the first time I saw this formulation of
Mark of decision process I I think it's
a very Natural Choice to consider this
agent to be a robot that interact with
our environment and of course this is
indeed uh have been well studied for
more than 40 years that using RL for
robotics um but maybe a key moment in
this whole development of whole deep ARL
is the success of dqn in 2015 and Alpha
go in 2016 where essentially the de the
Deep month researchers firstly showing
you can applying these DQ algorithms to
achieve continuous like human level
continuous control in different Atari
games uh it's not only one games but
like a lot of different games and one
single formulations and do not have too
many tricks still have some tricks but
it's still General enough to cover wide
range of games and also the arpa goal in
2016 which is rough when I started
research um so is so they apply this
problem on goal which is traditionally
people think the search space is too
large for any algorithms to to be
feasible and I think this these two
events really triggers people's interest
on using RL for something because maybe
like the search space of some in some TS
the search space of Robotics
manipulations is not so
large um and also there are also like
contributions from the simulator site
which including open I dream and DM
control they Define a set of different
continuous control task in the context
of Robotics and also the the greatest
contribution here is you can so they
Define a very good interface so that you
can applying de you can focusing on
developing your r aor
instead of considering you need to deal
with also the bottom level simulators
you you can only um so you can do this
research by writing python code and
simple Al algorithm terms instead of
need to considering oh how should I
Define these models and how do I
communicate with different C++
code and um all of
them all of them greatly increase the
interest on using r for robotics so of
course RL is keep increasing but it's
just significantly
increases um like in very recent years
so when we consider applying RL to
robotics there are definitely two
categories so first one is you can use
you can run your RL algorithms directly
in the real world in your real robot and
receive the interactions from from the
environment and another way is to use
seem to
real um and I'll describe them one by
one so here is a video of real word
RL um so real word RL is
very like it's very promising in terms
of that you can after you have this
setup you can leave it there and it
automatically improvements according to
your reward
functions and so this is one of the
examples I found pretty interesting this
is a quarter pack had learning to work
um Guided by the reward terms purely in
Real
World um I'll play it for a
while so this is after maybe one or two
hours uh of
Trials
um
no yeah after that it learns pretty
decent uh robustness
and and also maybe a little bit
generalization to different environments
so that's uh that's a like pretty good
results in real world R and there are
also of course challenges and research
hot research topics uh in real world R
so for example RL is very well known to
be sample un efficient because you rely
on trial and errors to collect a lot of
samples and also optim and and then
optimize your policy so therefore a
large a very large portion of research
focuses on Sample efficient RL which is
so you might see in that people
doing uh people doing some new R
improvements on Jo on openi gym or the
DM control that uh achieving some
promising control tasks within millions
of
samples and how the other challenge is
about the unsafe so in the context of
robotics directly deploying this real
world RL is not very safe uh so in the
previous example if you VI with
carefully um so
initially so the robots need to be
constrainted on some certain kind of
very small motions so it cannot give a
very high velocity or high amount of
force because the hardware may may be
break
and also there are also problem I mean
which I think is a very important
problems on real world RL which is the
rely on human labors to reset the
environments so in the previous video if
you if you remember so there is always a
human that moves the robot from from the
end positions to the beginning of the
positions so every time step a human
need to do that and there are also other
uh another aspect is how are you going
to Define reward in the real world so
this is Imagine working is a very like
semantically is a very well defined task
but if you want if you want to measure
the progress of working you need to you
need to detect you have you need to have
a accurate detection on what is the
position of the robot and it might be
okay if you are working in indoor
environment you have a like calibrated
camera for detecting these objects but
if you're going to consider the oying
this you know real um outdoor
environment so that's is pretty hard so
computer vision at that time is not
super good to achieve that and there
here are other examples of um just
giving some examples so there are also
learning real world RLS uh to rotate
this valve and uh to rotate this wall
with so need a detector on what kind of
so what is the position and orientation
of the wall and they what they did is to
place some sensors on the end of the uh
some
instrumental some other uh equipment to
get orientation of the S of the wall and
also this is a robotics opening a door
experiments and they need to have some
automatic reset process which is some
mechanical structure that automatically
close the door so these types of
examples kind of need to design for uh
for each kind of different different
task so this is this is pretty labor
intensive and on the other hand uh
compared to real word ARL is you can do
s to real and the advantage is kind of
the opposite of the disadvantage of real
world ARL so reward access reward is
very easy accessible from simulations so
in simulation all the velocities and
positions is well defined and then you
can just get that from one line of f
reset is also very easy because at each
episode you will just assign what is the
positions and orientations of the
objects and but the problem and the
challenge of sim to real is also the
opposite of real world RL which is after
you learning this policies in simulation
there is always a soral gap uh between
your policy Trend in simulation versus
deployed in the real
world and
in early like in 2018 2019 so there are
also a lot of attempts and there is even
a very hot debate on if we should still
invest in simal there is a workshop in
RS um which is so there is a very
interesting term called Sim to now which
is people work too much on simulations
and claim their algorithms is better by
comparing different simulation
benchmarks but now of them can transfer
to the real world so this is basically
simp to
know and what is makes this more worse
for RL to robotics is not only the
problem of Robotics but also the problem
of RL this is also a famous article uh
when I started to looking at RL so the
um I forgot to take the reference but
this is from um this is from Mila and I
think it's called Deep reinforcement
learning that matters so the dis the set
fact at that time is so this is two
learning curves and this tool learning
curve is produced by so you having some
prpo uh some policy gradient algorithms
running a running on a certain
Locomotion tasks on open dream and so in
the first in the first trial you
randomly sample five different random
seat and run your algorithms so it
produce this curve and and next time you
randomly sample another five different
random seat you and then you get a curve
like this so this is not a teric five
random seat this is really five two set
of randomly CH seat so even in this case
your policy will still have a reasonably
gap which which uh which indicates that
if you see a curve that improves in in
the paper it might not not be like truly
Improvement maybe just the C is
better um and also there are a lot of
other uh factors which is the code base
difference so there are lots of very
small engineering choice that will make
your policy either stability wise or
performance wise to be very different so
this is a very this is small
implementations um that are all of them
are considered Cor
but there are also some small difference
in terms of design choices and implement
the same algorithms on the same
environments and the learning curve is
significantly
different
and um some other examples including so
this is typically ARL training curves
which goes to episod returns goes to
very high and very stable and when
people are happy happy with set it
suddenly goes to very unstable stages
and in comparison if you are training
computer vision networks this is very
stable so the training curves of course
because of stochastic batch gradient
descent uh you have some slightly up and
down but after that the general trend of
your training Still Remains the Same
so uh so PE so at that time people will
tend to think it remains significantly
challenging to apply RL to Robotics and
people don't know how don't know how to
deal with not only the challenges from
robotics but also the challenges from
reinforcement learning it themselves and
so especially on complex systems such as
hands or legs there are really limited
number of success
examples and um so I think the the major
rbse of this line of work is driven by
simp thr and
of course there are also other uh
success examples but uh maybe the the
experiments that bring people's
attention to this back again is driven
by Sim and before we delve into what
work
exactly is does this work do uh we take
a we will then take a small detour from
reinforcement learning and talk a little
bit about uh basic concepts in
simulators
um before that any questions regarding
the previous
sections okay and as we as we have
already seen in previous sections the
simulation are kind of widely used in RL
research so for example the open AI G or
the DM
controls
and and people use simulators uh usually
in in two different ways so they can use
simulators to develop an algorithms so
either it can be an RL algorithms or
even modelbased control
algorithms and then what people want to
get from simulators is to get a sense of
what type of algorithms works and what
is a good set of
hyperparameters so after people
debugging and developing algorithms and
finding a good set of parameters they
can directly running these algorithms in
the real world so the simulation data is
used to tune your controller instead of
um get a model for that and on the other
hand there are also people using
simulator to using actually the
simulator data to turn your model and
deploy these models to the real world
and one uh distinct fact between these
two is in the later stage the point is
not SLE efficient anymore so because as
we will see in the a little bit later
slides so the current simulators runs
very fast and you do not need to worry
about oh my algorithms need like
hundreds of millions of SES to get a
stable state so SLE efficiency still
helps when in the iteration speed in
terms of you between your developing
algorithms trying to deploy and get a
new model it helps in this process but
the more important thing here now
becomes how stable is your training and
what is the performance of your your
algorithms okay simulators and here is
an overview I mean very simplified
overview of rigid body simulations this
SCE is credit to the PIP team so the
simulation simulation Loops run over
forward
Dynamics and uh forward Dynamics time
numerical time Integrations and cision
detections so in um in time Integrations
you are given you given the
accelerations of different rigid bodies
given the force and you want you have
some you have some algorithms or
techniques to update the velocities and
positions of all the rigid bodies in
your
environments and in certain cases uh
actually in many cases there will be
clle between either uh two rigid bodies
or your rigid body and the
environments um and then in this case
there will be techniques to detect and
resolve these condition
conditions and after that um you will
after that after this step you will get
updated velocities and positions of all
the objects and then you will compute
the accelerations and forces uh again
and for the time integration so this is
running in a loop defining on what is
your Abol lens and what is your time
Horizons so for the um let me see for
the forward Dynamics part so the forward
Dynamics is a process that given
positions and velocities and we want to
calculate accelerations of the different
rid bodies so in the simplest case if
you consider consider you only have a
point Mass you can uh you can calculate
that by just using FAL to
ma uh but you more a slightly more
complex case you uh so you have a rigid
body that involves orientations and
angular velocities you need to use this
equations to get that so the T equals to
the I here is the initial Matrix
depending on the mass distributions of
your objects
and the Omega do Omega dot is the
acceleration of your angular velocities
and there's another term which makes it
looks different from the fals to ma
which is really
consider when you have a rigid body that
rotates it does not always follow the
same rotation axis and the the rotation
axis may not pass into your center of
mass so there need to be some extra term
der DED from physics to for
that um and after that you can
calculate the updated velocities and
updated positions according to these a
few equations there are also something I
haven't mentioned which is at some point
there will be external force and the
force from contact at this uh executed
at this time step and uh the external so
you can essentially divide it by you
have a the effect of external Force
applied to the objects also something
which is which we called impulse uh that
is produced by the contact which I'll
describe in a series slide
later um so this is for the Motions so
how you get accelerations for rigid
bodies in robotics We Care More about
getting uh not only a single rigid
objects but it's a linked rigid body
which is a multi-body interactions so
consider you have a robot arm and have
seven degree freedoms and this robot arm
is
U uh the robot arm is essentially having
seven different links and they are
connected by a joint and the physics
becomes quite complicated if you write
that into Newtons formulations and this
is some uh and we have some tools for
that which is called L longin Dynamics
um in the last lecture we also talk
about little a little bit of that but in
this case what we are so a few concept
is when we talk about generalized
coordinates in
manipulation it really just mean you
have these revoluted draws and you have
SE maybe seven draws and then each of
The Joint angles is the generalized
coordinates so you have the seven joint
angles then the configuration of your
robot arm is uniquely defined so that's
the coordinates of your um your your
robot
arm and kinetic energy and potential
energy are also defined same as um as as
in the physics and generalize the force
and in this limited robot arm
manipulation examples this only means
how much torque you applied on each of
the
joints so the formulation is say if you
if you write down the uh kinetic energy
and potential energies and take a
derivative of uh the L so the L is T
minus U so you can get the formulation
of what is the torque on each of the
joints and the torque is essentially the
accelerations of the
rotations and one example which so you
can see a very complicated equations but
um but take into account that you have a
simulator and all this mass and length
and all these kind of values in
including M and L and also the Q dot is
which is the velocities Q Dot and Q is
the velocity and positions of the
objects so all of them are known they
are just a single scalers uh defined by
either your urdf or the velocity
position returned by your simulators and
it's kind of easy to get a relationship
between the uh Q double dot and the
torque you applied on the joint so given
given this is really to remember our
purpose is to get accelerations of
different joint and uh according to your
external out external control input in
this case all the other quantities is
known and you can get a relationship
between accelerations and the control
input this is how at each time step you
updated your angular velocities and then
uh as a turn change to your velocities
and also your
positions
um and after that there will be after
you get the updated position and
velocities there will be also a stage of
Collis check
um so the idea of collision check is
simply there are two phases the first
one is the broad face and also there is
another one which is a narrow phas broad
face is simply if you consider two
convex
objects if the two convex objects are
too close to each other they will be
considered possibly uh can collide with
each other and because this is very
broad you you can just uh you can just
uh calculate that by comparing first the
distance between Center of mass also
consider the shape of the object so what
is the uh what is the closest point
between two rigid
objects and for the narrow phas there
are rich literatures on that and there
are also well established algorithm to
implement that and this may be rather
very complicated and we are not going to
introduce in this class but if you're
interested you are welcome to check
these algorithms so usually that's very
sophisticated that you need to between
two time step you need to consider a lot
of things for example if there are two
small objects moving in very fast
velocities if you directly contain if
you directly consider the positions in
the current time step and the other time
step they may just penetrate with each
other without knowing they actually
penetrate and there are lot of
techniques to actually capture that
collisions and resolve that
collisions and there are also important
concept of in real world we do not
really usually we do not always have uh
convex objects and when we have a
complex objects in the real world uh if
we want to model a rather complex object
in simulations we also need to decompose
that into a lot of um comp compostion of
primitive convex
stapes so this is one convex
decomposition method which is
hcd um you can use optimization method
to run on each kind of vertices what is
the what is the possible way that
satisfy convexity together with being as
close as uh the original not convex
shapes and also
um this is how Collision resolve this is
how the simulator resolve collisions
again this deration is a little bit
complex and the point in this figure is
to
saying um in cision detection we
actually doing this so if you if you
update the position and velocities and F
there are some penetration between two
different objects so what we could do is
to apply in some Force represented by
the contact that trying to move these
two parts away so in the contact point
we can apply the impulse uh according to
how much you P how much between two
objects
penetrat and then what is the velocity
between the two objects and we doing
that for several iterations until some
constraint is satisfied so the
constraints can be you have two objects
they are not penetrated with each other
and they are also as close as when they
when they are having this
context and this is the correction term
which related to a few different
quantities such as the mass of two
objects also the initial Matrix of the
two objects also the r and N defined as
is uniquely defined by the contact
points
um okay uh I think we will break here
and after we have the break I'll
starting to talk about some examples of
the simulator we can use for uh robot
learning